westcoastuniversity.edu 2015-09-30

# Privacy Policy | WCU

This privacy notice discloses the privacy practices for www.westcoastuniversity.edu.  This privacy notice applies solely to information collected by this website, except where stated otherwise. 

## What personally identifiable information does West Coast University collect from me?

West Coast University collects information in several ways from different parts of our websites. Some personal information is gathered if you register with us. During registration, West Coast University may ask for personal information such as your name, email address, gender, zip/postal code, occupation, industry and personal interests.

In addition to registration, we may ask you for personal information at other times, including, (but not limited to), when you download a file (such as a .PDF file) from us, when you ask us to contact you, when you join our mailing list; and when you report a problem with one of our sites or services. If you contact West Coast University, we may keep a record of that correspondence. West Coast University may also occasionally ask users to complete surveys that we use for research. Wherever West Coast University collects personal information we make an effort to include a link to this Privacy Policy on that page.

To be removed from any future communication, email or otherwise, [click here.](http://westcoastuniversity.edu/cpl/opt-out.html)

## What are cookies and how does West Coast University use them?

As part of offering and providing customizable and personalized services, West Coast University may use cookies to store and sometimes track information about you. A cookie is a small amount of data that is sent to your browser from our web server and stored on your computer's hard drive.

 **Generally, we may use cookies to:**  
(1) Remind us of who you are and to access your information (stored on our computers) in order to deliver to you a better and more personalized service. For example, a cookie is set when you register or "Sign In" and is modified when you "Sign Out" of our services.  
(2) Automate certain areas of the West Coast University websites or online forms.  
(3) Estimate our audience size. Each browser accessing the West Coast University website is given a unique cookie which is then used to determine the extent of repeat usage, usage by a registered user versus by an unregistered user, and to help target advertisements based on user interests and behavior.  
(4) Measure certain traffic patterns, which areas of the West Coast University website you have visited, and your visiting patterns in the aggregate. We use this research to understand how our users' habits are similar or different from one another so that we can make each new experience on the West Coast University website a better one. We may use this information to better personalize the content, and promotions that you and other users will see on our sites.

West Coast University also collects IP Addresses, browser information and other computer information to report aggregate information to our marketing department.

You also have choices with respect to cookies. By modifying your browser preferences, you have the choice to accept all cookies, to be notified when a cookie is set, or to reject all cookies. Please refer to your browser's help page for further information about your options for controlling or monitoring cookies.

## How does West Coast University use my information?

West Coast University's primary goal in collecting personal information is to provide you, the user, with a customized experience on our websites. This includes personalization services and interactive communications, which are completely free to you.

West Coast University does research on our users' demographics, interests, and behavior based on the information provided to us upon registration, or from our server log files. We do this to better understand and serve our users. This research is compiled and analyzed on an aggregated basis.

## With whom does West Coast University share my information?

West Coast University will not disclose any of your personally identifiable information except when we have your permission. West Coast University may disclose account information in special cases when we have reason to believe that disclosing this information is necessary to identify, contact or bring legal action against someone who may be violating West Coast University's Terms of Service or may be causing injury to or interference with (either intentionally or unintentionally) West Coast University's rights or property, other West Coast University users, or anyone else that could be harmed by such activities. West Coast University may disclose or access account information when we believe in good faith that the law requires it and for administrative and other purposes that we deem necessary to maintain, service, and improve our products and services.

West Coast University does not sell or rent user information to anyone. We will notify you at the time of data collection or transfer if your data will be shared with a third party and you will always have the option of not permitting the transfer. If you do not wish to allow your data to be shared, you can choose not to use a particular service or not to participate in certain promotions or contests.

## How does West Coast University secure my information?

We take precautions to protect your information. When you submit sensitive information via the website, your information is protected both online and offline.  Wherever we collect sensitive information (such as credit card data), that information is encrypted and transmitted to us in a secure way. While we use encryption to protect sensitive information transmitted online, we also protect your information offline. Only employees who need the information to provide you with the service requested have access to your information. The computers/servers on which we store personally identifiable information are kept in a secure environment.

## How could my submitted information be corrected or what do I do if I have concerns over misuse of my personal data?

You may opt out of any future contacts from us at any time. You can do the following at any time by contacting us via the email address or phone number provided on our website:

  * See what data we have about you, if any.
  * Change/correct any data we have about you.
  * Have us delete any data we have about you.
  * Express any concern you have about our use of your data.

## How will I be notified of any privacy policy changes?

 If a substantial privacy notice revision occurs, you will be notified by the university and the new privacy statement will be available for review. 

## What else should I know about my privacy?

Please keep in mind that whenever you voluntarily disclose personal information online - for example on message boards, through email, or in instant message or chat areas - that this information can be collected and used by others. In short, if you post personal information online that is accessible to the public, you may receive unsolicited messages from other parties in return.

Unfortunately, no data transmission over the Internet can be guaranteed to be 100% secure. As a result, while we strive to protect your personal information, West Coast University cannot ensure or warrant the security of any information you transmit to us or from our online products or services, and you do so at your own risk. Once we receive your transmission, we make our best effort to ensure its security on our systems.

Ultimately, you are solely responsible for maintaining the secrecy of your passwords and/or any account information. Please be careful and responsible whenever you're online.
